Find your voice.
The King's Speech is a drama, history film directed by Tom Hooper.
The King's Speech tells the story of the man who became King
George VI, the father of Queen Elizabeth II.
After his brother abdicates, George ('Bertie') reluctantly assumes the throne.
Plagued by a dreaded stutter and considered unfit to be king, Bertie engages
the help of an unorthodox speech therapist named Lionel Logue.
Through a set of unexpected techniques, and as a result of an unlikely friendship,
Bertie is able to find his voice and boldly lead the country into war.
King George VI, played by Colin Firth.
Lionel Logue, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Queen Elizabeth, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
King Edward VIII, played by Guy Pearce.
Winston Churchill, played by Timothy Spall.
King George V, played by Michael Gambon.
The King's Speech is a 2010 historical drama film directed
by Tom Hooper and written by David Seidler.
Colin Firth plays the future King George VI who, to cope with a stammer, sees Lionel
Logue, an Australian speech and language therapist played by Geoffrey Rush.
The men become friends as they work together, and after his brother abdicates the throne, the new king relies on Logue
to help him make his first wartime radio broadcast upon Britain's declaration of war on Germany in 1939.
Seidler read about George VI's life after learning to manage a
stuttering condition he developed during his youth.
He started writing about the relationship between the therapist and his royal patient as early as the 1980s, but at the
request of the King's widow, Queen Elizabeth the Queen Mother, postponed work until she died in 2002.
He later rewrote his screenplay for the stage to focus on the
essential relationship between the two protagonists.
Nine weeks before filming began, the filmmakers learned of the existence of notes written by Logue that were being used by his grandson Mark and
Peter Conradi as the basis of a book, and were granted permission to incorporate material from the notes and book into the script.
Principal photography took place in London and around
Britain from November 2009 to January 2010.
Hard light was used to give the story a greater resonance and wider-than-normal lenses
were employed to recreate the Duke of York's feelings of constriction.
A third technique Hooper employed was the off-centre framing of characters.
The King's Speech was a major box office and critical success.
It was widely praised by film critics for its visual style, art
direction, screenplay, directing, score, and acting.
Other commentators discussed the film's representation of historical detail,
especially the reversal of Winston Churchill's opposition to abdication.
The film received many awards and nominations,
particularly for Colin Firth's performance.
At the 83rd Academy Awards, The King's Speech received 12 Oscar nominations, more than any other film in
that year, and subsequently won four, including Best Picture and Best Actor for Firth.
Censors initially gave it adult ratings due to profanity, though these were later revised downward after
criticism by the makers and distributors in the UK and some instances of swearing were muted in the US.
On a budget of £8 million, it earned over £250 million internationally.
The film explores themes of great britain, marriage, stutter, monarchy, palace.
The tone is emotional and intense.